Guide to the Anne L. Halpern Washington Metropolitan Area Dance collection, 1963-2004 MS2218
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Anne L. Halpern Washington Metropolitan Area Dance collection
1963-2004
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Halpern, Anne L.
MS2218
0.5 Linear Feet
The Georgetown Dance Studios Inc. was co-founded by Jan Van Dyke (1941- ) and John Gamble in 1967. Jan Van Dyke has been an active member of the Washington Metropolitan dance community since her graduation from George Washington University in 1967 with a M.A. in dance education. Along with co-founding Georgetown Dance Studios Inc., she established her own dance studio, Dance Place, located in Adams Morgan, in 1972. CODA(Contemporary Dancers of Alexandria) and Dance Studio are two Washington Metropolitan Area dance studios founded by Hedi Pope(1924 - ). Hedi established and ran Dance Studio in Alexandria, Virginia from 1947 - 1980. CODA was created in the late 1970's and was a premier local dance group that performed through the 1980's. Hedi Pope has trained three generations of students including Jan Van Dyke.
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Acquisition Information
The Anne L. Halpern Washington Metropolitan Area Dance collection was donated by Anne L. Halpern in 2007. A second small donation was made, January 31, 2011 (2011.005) A third small donation was added February 21, 2018 (2018.009)
Historical or Biographical Note
The Georgetown Dance Studios Inc. was co-founded by Jan Van Dyke (1941- ) and John Gamble in 1967. Jan Van Dyke has been an active member of the Washington Metropolitan dance community since her graduation from George Washington University in 1967 with a M.A. in dance education. Along with co-founding Georgetown Dance Studios Inc., she established her own dance studio, Dance Place, located in Adams Morgan, in 1972. CODA(Contemporary Dancers of Alexandria) and Dance Studio are two Washington Metropolitan Area dance studios founded by Hedi Pope(1924 - ). Hedi established and ran Dance Studio in Alexandria, Virginia from 1947 - 1980. CODA was created in the late 1970's and was a premier local dance group that performed through the 1980's. Hedi Pope has trained three generations of students including Jan Van Dyke.
Collection Scope and Content
This collection contains performance programs, posters, fliers and newspaper clippings. The material deals with various dance companies performing in the Washington metropolitan area in the 1960's ,1970's and early 1980's. The collection material dates from 1963-2004.
Ballet companies mentioned include: the Georgetown Workshop, and Georgetown dance Studio Inc., CODA(Contemporary Dancers of Alexandria), The Washington Dance Repertory Company, the National Ballet, the George Washington University Dance Co. and Dance Studio.
The bulk of the materials are performance programs for both the Georgetown Dance Studio Inc. and CODA.
Arrangement
Arranged chronologically.
Ballet; Art -- Study and teaching -- Washington (D.C.); Performing arts; Washington Metropolitan Area; Dance companies; George Washington University; Van Dyke, Jan; Pope, Hedi; Gamble, John
- CODA and the Dance Studio materials, 1963-1985 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  General note
  This folder contains materials relating to Washington Metropolitan Area dance companies CODA and the Dance Studio and their creator Hedi Pope. Included are fourteen performance programs, two are Dance Studio, twelve are CODA, two Dance Studio posters, one flier, and six newspaper article and review clippings dealing with CODA.
- Jan Van Dyke materials, 1968-1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  This folder contains ten Georgetown Dance Studio Inc. performance and workshop programs dating from 1968 - 1969, one program for Two Dances Created for the Corcoran Gallery of Art from 1979, one photo image of Jan Van Dyke and two Georgetown Dance Studio Inc. performance posters.
- Miscellaneous Dance Companies materials, 1969-1982 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  This folder contains materials pertaining to miscellaneous Washington Metropolitan Area dance companies. Dance companies include: The National Ballet, the Dance Exchange, the George Washington Dance Co., and the Washington Dance Repertory Company.
- Accession 2011.005 records, 1977-1989 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  General
  This file contains programs and newspaper articles related to the work of dancer Jan Van Dyke who also performed under the name Jan Taylor.
- City Dance programs, 1978-1980; MS2218 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Miscellaneous Metro area dace programs, 1978-1991; MS2218 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- CODA Programs, 1979-1986; MS2218 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Washington Post article about CODA, 1982 April 07; MS2218 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- The Center Dance Company programs, 1984-2004; MS2218 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Kathy Harty Gray Dance Theater, 1990-1996; MS2218 (Box 2, Folder 4)